Guide to the Robert J. Leach papers, 1930-1998
Leach, Robert J. papers, 1930-1998
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert J. Leach papers, 1930-1998
7609
Robert J. Leach
13.3 cubic ft.; 197 tape recordings.
Correspondence, manuscripts, diaries, audio recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection documents Leach's determination and expression of his sexual identity, his life as a closeted gay, his coming out, and his emotional life as a gay American abroad and on Nantucket Island, as well as the details of his family life, friendships, and Leach family genealogy. The collection also includes correspondence from Robert Leach describing his donations, providing context for his collection at Cornell.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert J. Leach was born on November 4, 1916 in Reading, Massachusetts. He attended Marietta College in Ohio from 1934-1938 and received his Master's degree in History from Ohio State University. In 1939, Leach joined the Religious Society of Friends and has remained active as a Quaker member and elder since that time. Throughout his youth, he experienced crushes on boys that he tried to ignore, and in 1941, he fell in love with a man for the first time. They did not, however, get involved. A conscientious objector during World War II, Leach served in the Civilian Public Service from 1942-1946. From 1946-1950, Leach was an assistant professor of History at Salem College in North Carolina. In 1950 and 1951, Leach completed all of his course work for a doctoral degree at the University of Geneva, and in 1951 was appointed head of History at the International School of Geneva. He has maintained a residence in Switzerland ever since. He remained at the School for thirty years where he co-founded the International Baccalaureate Program. His research has included comparative religion and comparative civilization, although his most recent publications have focused on whaling and Nantucket Quaker history.
In 1953, he married Jean Frances, who had won Junior Wimbledon in 1938, and who had taught auto-mechanics in the British Army during the War. He and Jean had two children, David R.F. Leach, in 1954, and Felicity M.K. Leach, in 1955. David became a lecturer in Molecular Genetics in Scotland at Edinburgh University, and Felicity became a world level rowing champion and an expert in audio visual studies. Before Robert and Jean married, he told her that he believed he was bisexual. Her response was, "That is your business." They were happily married for almost 28 years. After Jean's death in 1981, Leach identified himself as gay and told his children and later his grandchildren, all of whom reacted very supportively. He also sent a "coming out" letter to five hundred friends and acquaintances, about half of whom Leach claims have avoided him since. From 1981-1982 and 1993-1994, Leach traveled around the world. The earlier trip gave rise to relationships with two Thai men named Noui and Toek (last names not provided). Leach's relationship with Toek lasted over four years, and Toek has since had a sex change operation. The relationship is well documented in the collection.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The papers of Robert J. Leach consist of journals with consistent daily entries (1930-1986), written and audio taped reflections on those journals (1975-1979), autobiographical manuscripts (1963-1985), incoming as well as outgoing correspondence (1928-1994), and appointment calendars (1955-1996). The Leach papers document his determination and expression of his sexual identity, his life as a closeted gay, his coming out, and his emotional life as a gay American abroad and on Nantucket Island. There is abundant reflection on his family relations, and elaborate and painstaking descriptions of the narrative of his rich life. The collection also includes several miscellaneous items including a commonplace book of A. Judson Leach (RJL's father) from the 1880s, an unidentified commonplace book from 1969 (probably owned by Jean Leach), and several of Leach's address books. The collection includes correspondence from Robert Leach describing his donations and providing context for his collection at the Cornell Archives' Human Sexuality Collection.
Robert Leach's papers having to do with his career as an international educator are located at the Archives of the International School of Geneva (Switzerland). Papers focusing on his Quaker activities are located at the Friends Historical Library at Swarthmore College, Pennsylvania, and at the Archives of Geneva M.M. of the Religious Society of Friends. Books and other items will be deposited at Dialoguegay in Geneva, Switzerland (57 Avenue, Wendt) and the Peter Foulger Museum on Nantucket.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Leach, Robert J.; Leach, Jean.; Marietta College.
Subjects:
Quakers--History.; Gays' writings.; Coming out (Sexual orientation); Gays--Social life and customs.; Closeted gays.
Places:
Nantucket (Mass.)--Social life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audio tapes.; Commonplace books.; Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 25, 26, and 28 are restricted and closed for research use until 2018.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The lack of Volumes XXI and XXIII is the result of the original misnumbering of the volumes by the donor.
CONTAINER LIST
- Volume I, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Volume II, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Volume III, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Volume IV, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Volume V, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Volume VI, 1930, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Volume VII, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Volume VIII, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Volume IX - Five Year Diary, 1932-36 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Volume X, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Volume XI, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Volume XII, 1937 -38 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Volume XIII, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Volume XIV, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Volume XV (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Volume XVI, 1941- (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Volume XVII (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Volume XVIII (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Volume XIX (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Volume XXII, 1947- (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Addendum to Vol XXIII, 1948 - 49 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Volume XXIV (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Volume XXV, 1950- (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Volume XXVI, 1951- (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Volume XXVII, 1953- (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Volume XX (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Volume XXXI, 1962 - 65 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Volume XXXII, 1965 - 68 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Volume XXVIII, 1956- (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Volume XXIX, 1958- (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Volume XXX, 1960- (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Volume XXXIII, 1968 - 70 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Minutes of Pocomoke Friends, 1944- (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Reflections on My Journal, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Volume XXXIV, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
- Volume XXXV, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
- Volume XXXVI, 1973-1975 (Box 4)
- Volume XXXVII, 1975-1977 (Box 4)
- Volume XXXVIII, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
- Volume XXXIX, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
- Volume XL, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
- Volume XLI, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
- FROM THE INNER SHORE TO THE FAR OUT ISLAND, 1963-1967; Book IX: The Fund-Raising Exploration Years, 1959-1969, THE INTERNATIONAL BACCALAUREATE DECADE (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- FROM THE INNER SHORE TO THE FAR OUT ISLAND, 1959-1969; Book X: 1966-1970,THE INTERNATIONAL BACCALAUREATE DECADE, The Fading of the Fund-Raising Exploration Years (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
- FROM THE INNER SHORE TO THE FAR OUT ISLAND, 1969-1972; Book Eleven: THE CHILDREN'S HIGH SCHOOL YEARS (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
- FROM THE INNER SHORE TO THE FAR OUT ISLAND, 1975-1977; Book Twelve: THE AQUARIAN REVOLUTION (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
- FROM THE INNER SHORE TO THE FAR OUT ISLAND, 1976-1980; Book Thirteen: YEARS OF REALISING MYSELF (Box 4, Folder 16-18)
- FROM THE INNER SHORE TO THE FAR OUT ISLAND, 1980-1982; Book Fourteen (Part I): YEARS OF RETIREMENT AND TRIP AROUND THE WORLD (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
- FROM THE INNER SHORE TO THE FAR OUT ISLAND, 1980-1982; Book Fourteen (Part II): YEARS OF RETIREMENT AND TRIP AROUND THE WORLD (Box 4, Folder 21-23)
- FROM THE INNER SHORE TO THE FAR OUT ISLAND, Book Fifteen: NOUI; AND TOEK; THE THAI INVOLVEMENT; 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 24-26)
- Letters from Robert Leach to his cousin Myrtle, 1958-1994 (Box 4, Folder 27-29)
- "Miscellaneous early data not included elsewhere", 1917-1951 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- A. Judson Leach to Robert J. Leach and Mary K. Leach Jr., 1928-30 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- A. Judson Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- A. Judson Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1935: Jan.-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- A. Judson Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1935: May-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- A. Judson Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- A. Judson Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- A. Judson Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- A. Judson Leach to "Frank" (unidentified), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- A. Judson Leach to Grace Lewis Cook, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1935: Jan.-June (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1935: July -Dec. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1936: Jan.-May (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1936: June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1939: Jan.-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1939: May-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1940: Jan.-May (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1940: June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1941: Jan.-June (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1941: July-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1942: Jan.-May (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1942: June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1943: Jan.-June (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1943: July-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1944: Jan.-June (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1944: July-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1945: Jan.-May (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1945: June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1947: Jan.-June (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1947: July-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1948: Jan.-Sept. (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1948: Oct.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach & family, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach & family, 1954-55 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach & family, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Mary K. Leach Sr. to Robert J. Leach & family, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach (some also to Mary K. Leach Jr.), 1940-42 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1930 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1934 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1935: Jan.-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1935: May-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1936: Jan.-May (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1936: June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1937: Jan.-May (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1937: June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1938: Jan.-May (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1938: June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1940 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1941 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- Robert J. Leach to A. Judson Leach and Mary K. Leach Sr., 1942 (Box 5, Folder 58)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr., 1943 (Box 5, Folder 59)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 60)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 62)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 63)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Mary K. Leach Jr. and Rachel K. Osgood ["Aunt Rae"]), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1950 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1951: Jan.-May (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (somealso to Rachel K. Osgood), 1951: June-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1952: Jan.-Apr. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1952: May-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1953 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1955 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. (some also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Robert J. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr. and her medical aids (some from early 1956 also to Rachel K. Osgood), 1956-1962 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Rachel K. Osgood to Robert J. Leach, Jean F. Leach to Mary K. Leach Sr., Mary K. Leach Sr. to Myrtle K. Barr, 1933-1957 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Rachel K. Osgood to Robert J. Leach (starting in 1953, also to Jean F. Leach), 1946-1956 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Robert J. Leach to Rachel K. Osgood, 1939, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Mary K. Leach Jr. to Robert J. Leach, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Mary K. Leach Jr. to Robert J. Leach, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Mary K. Leach Jr. to Robert J. Leach, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Mary K. Leach Jr. to Robert J. Leach, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Mary K. Leach Jr. to Robert J. Leach, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Mary K. Leach Jr. to Robert J. Leach, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Mary K. Leach Jr. to Robert J. Leach, 1945-1947 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Mary K. Leach Jr. to Robert J. Leach, 1948-1951 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Margaret W. Currier to Robert J. Leach, 1940s? (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Margaret W. Currier to Robert J. Leach, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Margaret W. Currier to Robert J. Leach, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Margaret W. Currier to Robert J. Leach, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Margaret W. Currier to Robert J. Leach, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Robert J. Leach to Margaret W. Currier, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1963, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Jean F. Leach to Robert J. Leach (some also to and from Felicity K. Leach, and David J. Leach), 1970, 1973, 1975-79 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Robert J. Leach to Jean F. Leach, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Robert J. Leach to Jean F. Leach, 1956: Jan.-Feb. (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Robert J. Leach to Jean F. Leach, 1956: Mar.-Apr. (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Robert J. Leach to Jean F. Leach, 1958, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Robert J. Leach to Jean F. Leach, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Robert J. Leach to Jean F. Leach, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Robert J. Leach to Jean F. Leach, 1969-1974 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Robert J. Leach to Jean F. Leach, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Felicity K. Leach to David J. Leach, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1961, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1976: Jan.-Mar. (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1976: Apr.-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1977: Jan.-May (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1978: Jan.-Apr. (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1979: May-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Felicity K. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Robert J. Leach to Felicity K. Leach, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Robert J. Leach to Felicity K. Leach, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Robert J. Leach to Felicity K. Leach, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Robert J. Leach to Felicity K. Leach, 1982-83, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Robert J. Leach to Felicity K. Leach, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Robert J. Leach to Felicity K. Leach & family, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 63)
- Robert J. Leach to Felicity K. Leach & family, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 64)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 65)
- David J. Leach to Robert J., Jean F., and Felicity M. K. Leach, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 66)
- David J. Leach to Robert J., Jean F., and Felicity M. K. Leach, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 67)
- David J. Leach to Robert J., Jean F., and Felicity M. K. Leach, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 68)
- David J. Leach to Robert J., Jean F., and Felicity M. K. Leach, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 69)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach (some also to Felicity M. K. Leach), 1977 (Box 6, Folder 70)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 71)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. & Jean F. Leach, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. Leach (one Jan. letter also to Jean F. Leach), 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. Leach, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- David J. Leach to Robert J. Leach (one also to "Toek"), 1985-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Robert J. Leach to David J. Leach, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Robert J. Leach to David J. Leach, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Robert J. Leach to David J. Leach & family (some also to Felicity M. K. Leach), 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Robert J. Leach to David J. Leach & family, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Robert J. Leach to David J. Leach & family, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Jean F. Leach to David J. Leach, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Jean F. Leach to David J. Leach, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Jean F. Leach to Felicity M. K. Leach, 1969, 1972, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Jean F. Leach to Felicity M. K. Leach, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Jean F. Leach to Felicity M. K. Leach, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Robert J. Leach to Katherine and Mary Lyle, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- A. Judson Leach: Scrapbook of quotations from time as a student at Brown University, 1880s (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Jean F. Leach [?]: Notebook, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Robert J. Leach: Appointment Book, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Robert J. Leach: Appointment Book, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Robert J. Leach: Appointment Book, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Robert J. Leach: Appointment Book, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Robert J. Leach: Appointment Book, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Robert J. Leach: Appointment Book, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Robert J. Leach: Appointment Book, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Robert J. Leach: Appointment Book, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Robert J. Leach: "Desk Diary", 1994 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Robert J. Leach: "Desk Diary", 1995 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Robert J. Leach: "Desk Diary", 1996 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- A. Judson Leach: untitled sermon given at the Fifth Congregational Meeting House of Edgartown, Massachusetts, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- International Diary, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Record of Trips and Conference, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- RJL Journal, Volume XLII, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Volume XLIII, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Volume XLIV, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Volume XLV, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Volume XLVI, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Marjorie ? to Robert J. Leach (3/21/41 annotated), 1934-1941 (Box 7, Folder 39)